A Guide to the Alexandria School of Nursing Collection 1894-1987
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
The Alexandria School of Nursing 1894-1987
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-14
14 linear ft. (22 boxes, ca. 1,135 items)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Material acquired from The Alexandria Hospital in 1990. The material in boxes 19 - 22 were received in December 2011 from Randolph Pillow, Seattle, Wa.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Alexandria Hospital School of Nursing began on November 1, 1894, when Marjorie Adamson established a small training school at the Alexandria Hospital. It was the fourth school of nursing to be established in the Commonwealth of Virginia. The original two year program began with two "pupil nurses," who received their diplomas on December 1, 1896.
As a graduate of the Glasgow Royal Infirmary in Scotland, Marjorie Adamson was both a physician and a nurse, and her professional background inspired her to establish a school that would promote excellence. The Board of Lady Managers was the governing board of the Hospital and the School and Marjorie Adamson proposed to the Board that the School offer general training for nurses using a curriculum that was the same as that used in the leading training schools in the South.
The Alexandria Hospital School of Nursing quickly established a reputation for excellence, and the course of study included lectures from physicians, and clinical experience in community nursing in the homes of Alexandria residents. In 1911 under the leadership of Naomi Simmons, the School increased the length of training to three years, became affiliated with the Episcopal Eye, Ear, Nose and Throat Hospital in Washington D.C., and required graduates to take the State Board examination to obtain licensure. The curriculum covered such subjects as anatomy, symptomatology, EENT, dietetics, materia medica, physiology, hygiene, surgical technique and emergency, obstetrics, gynecology, children's diseases, anesthetics, urinalysis, bacteriology, massage, and practical nursing.
When an entering student successfully completed the two month probationary period, she was given a cap to signify acceptance as a student nurse. Upon graduation, the cap was decorated with a black band. In 1916, Fannie Carter, a graduate of George Washington University, became the Superintendent of Nursing and Director of the School, a position she held for 21 years. During her tenure, admission requirements were raised, classes were held for four hours a day, a full-time instructor was hired, and History of Nursing was added to the curriculum. In 1928, an arrangment was made with the University of Virginia Hospital for an affiliation in pediatrics. The School closed from 1933 to 1936 due to financial difficulties incurred as a result of the Depression.
In 1943, Alexandria Hospital received approval to provide training for Cadet Nurses to help during World War II. The program continued until 1945. In 1944 the affiliation in Pediatric Nursing was switched to Children's Hospital in Washington D.C. and an affiliation in Psychiatric Nursing was established with St. Elizabeth's Hospital in Washington, D.C. In 1956 the Medical Nursing Library was established and in 1958 the School received full accreditation from the National League for Nursing. Also in 1958 married students were allowed at the School, and it became the first school in the State of Virginia to admit male nursing students.
Throughout the 1960's the number of faculty increased, and in 1968, the School of Nursing became a separate department in the Alexandria Hospital organization. In 1974, the entire hospital moved from Duke Street to Seminary Road, student dormitories closed, and the School became a commuter facility. All courses were taught at the School of Nursing, affiliations with other hospitals ended, and Alexandria Hospital remained the primary clinical facility.
After a two year review, the Board of Directors of Alexandria Hospital decided in March of 1984, to phase out the School of Nursing program and close the School in June of 1987. Qualified applicants had declined over the years as nursing students favored the four year baccalaureate programs over the three year clinical diploma program. Alumni and the final fourteen members of the 1987 graduating class joined in closing activities at the School that focused on "Celebrating a Proud History," and emphasized the legacy of high standards and values that graduates of the Alexandria Hospital School of Nursing contributed to their profession over the years.
Scope and Content
The Alexandria Hospital School of Nursing Collection is comprised of 22 boxes of papers and archival material, including photographs, manuscripts, correspondence, newspaper clippings, reports, Yearbooks, nursing caps and uniforms.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by administrative/curriculum, alumnae minutes & other materials, photos, slides, tapes, and artifacts. Boxes 19 through 21 contain Yearbooks arranged in date order. Box 22 includes administrative reports and minutes.
Contents List
- THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING 1894-1987 1987/ca., TMs (Box-folder 001-001)
- HISTORY OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING 1894-1987 1977/ca., TMs (MIMEO) (Box-folder 001-002)
- HISTORY OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING N.D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 001-003)
- UNTITLED HISTORY OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING N.D., TMs (Box-folder 001-004)
- UNTITLED HISTORY OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING N.D., TMs (Box-folder 001-005)
- HISTORY N.D., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-006)
- UNTITLED HISTORY OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING N.D., TMs (Box-folder 001-007)
- UNTITLED HISTORIES OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING N.D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 001-008)
- LETTER FROM DORIS S. SUDDARTH TO MARGARET HENRY 1973/04/17, TL (CC) (Box-folder 001-009)
- SPECIAL TO THE WASHINGTON POST FOR SUNDAY RELEASE N.D., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-010)
- LETTER FROM RUBY SIMMONS TO DOROTHY L. MCMILLAN 1951/02/28, TLS (Box-folder 001-011)
- ACADEMY HAS VIVID HISTORY 1969/04/01, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (P) (Box-folder 001-012)
  THE ALEXANDRIA GAZETTE, March 1, 1969
- LETTER FROM NAOMI SIMMONS KLIPSTEIN TO LEE ANN KELLEY 1955, ALS (P) (Box-folder 001-013)
- SPEECH BY DR. GEORGE KLIPSTEIN 1911/12/16, TMs (P) (Box-folder 001-014)
- REGULATIONS OF THE ALEXANDRIA INFIRMARY N.D., REPRINT (Box-folder 001-015)
- GENERAL INFORMATION - HISTORY N.D., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-016)
- RECRUITMENT N.D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 001-017)
- EXCERPT TAKEN FROM MINUTES OF BOARD OF LADY MANAGERS MEETING 1911, AMs (Box-folder 001-018)
- CAVALCADE OF NURSING FASHIONS 1975/11/06, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 001-019)
  THE VIRGINIA DELEGATE, November 6, 1975
- LETTER FROM IRENE M. ROSZEL TO EUGENIA K. SPALDING 1943/11/13, TL (CC) (Box-folder 001-020)
- MATERIALS RE U.S. CADET NURSE CORPS N.D., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-021)
- LETTER FROM LUCILE PETRY TO DIRECTORS OF SCHOOLS OF NURSING 1943/11/11, TMemo (P) (Box-folder 001-022)
- AIR FORCE NURSE CORPS PROMOTION LISTING - ANNABELLE M. MONTGOMERY GRYWALSKI 1950, TMemo (Box-folder 001-023)
- AIR FORCE NURSE CORPS PROMOTION LISTING - JACQUELYN F. BRODIE 1951, TMemo (Box-folder 001-024)
- LETTER FROM CHARLES M. GOFF TO CECIL C. SMITH 1959/02/13, TL (CC) (Box-folder 001-025)
- CONTENT OF COURSE - TUBERCULOSIS NURSING N.D., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-026)
- CLASS SCHEDULE - TUBERCULOSIS NURSING 1958, TMS (CC) (Box-folder 001-027)
- CONTENT OF COURSE - TUBERCULOSIS NURSING N.D., TMs (CC) (Box-folder 001-028)
- INFORMATION RE: CATAWBA SANATORIUM 1956/ca., TMs (Box-folder 001-029)
- LETTER FROM MARY L. LUCAS TO HELEN G. STATTS 1958/05/28, TLS (Box-folder 001-030)
- POSTCARD FROM MARY L. LUCAS TO HELEN STATTS N.D., APCS (Box-folder 001-031)
- THE NURSES' COTTAGE AT CATAWBA SANATORIUM VIRGINIA 1945, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-032)
- THE BOARD OF LADY MANAGERS OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL HISTORY 1871-1980 1980/ca., REPRINT (P) (Box-folder 001-033)
- THE BOARD OF LADY MANAGERS 1954/ca., TMs (P) (Box-folder 001-034)
- LETTER FROM DOROTHY L. MCMILLAN TO THELMA BROWN 1951/07/13, TL (CC) (Box-folder 001-035)
- LETTER FROM EDITH HARPER TO CAROLYN BERRY 1970/12/01, TL (CC) (Box-folder 001-036)
- LETTER FROM CAROLYN BERRY TO MADAME 1970/11/24, TLS (Box-folder 001-037)
- ALEXANDRIA INFIRMARY ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1893, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-038)
- ALEXANDRIA INFIRMARY ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1894, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-039)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1911, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-040)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1914, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-041)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1916, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-042)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1917, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-043)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1930, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-044)
- EXCERPTS FROM ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORTS 1931-1939, TMs (P) (Box-folder 001-045)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1934, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-046)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1942, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-047)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1945, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-048)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1930, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-049)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1943-1944, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-050)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL ANNUAL REPORT EXCERPT 1945, REPORT (P) (Box-folder 001-051)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1947, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-052)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1949, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-053)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1951, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-054)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1956/ca., PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-055)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1957, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-056)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1959-1961, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-057)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1961-1963, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-058)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1964-1965, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-059)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING TEMPORARY BULLETIN 1964-1965, TMs (MIMEO) (Box-folder 001-060)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1964, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-061)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1965-1966, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-062)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1966-1967, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-063)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING ANNOUNCEMENT 1967, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-064)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING BULLETIN/ANNOUNCEMENT 1968-1970, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-065)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING BULLETIN/ANNOUNCEMENT 1970-1971, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-066)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING BULLETIN/ANNOUNCEMENT 1971-1972, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-067)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING BULLETIN/ANNOUNCEMENT 1973-1975, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-068)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING BULLETIN/ANNOUNCEMENT 1975-1977, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-069)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CATALOG 1976-1978, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-070)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CATALOG 1978-1980, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-071)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CATALOG 1979-1981, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-072)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CATALOG 1981-1983, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-073)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CATALOG 1982-1984, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-074)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CATALOG 1984-1987, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 001-075)
- CAPPING SPEECH (MARILYN COOK) 1977, TMs (Box-folder 002-001)
- CAPPING SPEECH N.D., TMs (Box-folder 002-002)
- CAPPING SPEECH (DIANE WILLIAMS) 1983, TMs (Box-folder 002-003)
- CAPPING SPEECH (MARGUERITE M. SALZARULO) 1981, TMs (P) (Box-folder 002-004)
- CAPPING SPEECH (ANN MULHAUSER) 1979, TMs (P) (Box-folder 002-005)
- CAPPING SPEECH 1969, TMs (MIMEO) (Box-folder 002-006)
- CAPPING SPEECH (GWEN POARE) 1976, TMs (Box-folder 002-007)
- CAPPING SPEECH (DOATIE HARSHMAN) N.D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 002-008)
- CAPPING AN ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL TRADITION 1985/04/15, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 002-009)
- A CAPPING PRAYER 1973, TMs (Box-folder 002-010)
- CODE FOR PROFESSIONAL NURSES N.D., TMs (Box-folder 002-011)
- CANDLE LIGHTING SERVICE N.D., TMs (MIMEO) (Box-folder 002-012)
- BLESS THESE CAPS (SONG) N.D., TMs (P) (Box-folder 002-013)
- BLESS THESE CAPS (SONG) N.D., AMs (P) (Box-folder 002-014)
- FLORENCE NIGHTINGALE PLEDGE N.D., TMs (MIMEO) (Box-folder 002-015)
- FLORENCE NIGHTINGALE PLEDGE N.D., CERTIFICATE (Box-folder 002-016)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1950/04/19, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-017)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM AND INVITATION 1951/04/30, PROGRAM, PRINTED CARD" (Box-folder 002-018)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM AND INVITATION 1952/04/19, PROGRAM, PRINTED CARD" (Box-folder 002-019)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM AND INVITATION 1953/04/02, PROGRAM, PRINTED CARD" (Box-folder 002-020)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM AND INVITATION 1954/04/08, PROGRAM, PRINTED CARD" (Box-folder 002-021)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM AND INVITATION 1955/02/24, PROGRAM, PRINTED CARD" (Box-folder 002-022)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1956/04/11, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-023)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1957/04/31, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-024)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1958/04/09, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-025)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1959/04/15, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-026)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1961/04/22, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-027)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM AND INVITATION 1962/04/21, PROGRAM, PRINTED CARD" (Box-folder 002-028)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1963/04/20, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-029)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1964/04/18, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-030)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1965/04/17, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-031)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1966/04/16, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-032)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1968/04/17, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-033)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1969/04/17, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-034)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1970/04/13, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-035)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1971/04/11, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-036)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1972/04/10, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-037)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1973/04/09, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-038)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1974/04/01, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-039)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1975/04/21, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-040)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1976/04/12, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-041)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1977/04/11, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-042)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1978/04/10, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-043)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1980/04/07, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-044)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1981/04/06, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-045)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1984/04/02, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-046)
- CAPPING CEREMONY PROGRAM 1985/04/08, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-047)
- BLACK BAND DINNER FETES NURSING JUNIORS N.D., NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 002-048)
- GRADUATION INVITATION 1913/06/05, PRINTED CARD (Box-folder 002-049)
- GRADUATION PROGRAM 1915/05/07, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-050)
- GRADUATION INVITATION 1919/10/15, PRINTED CARD (Box-folder 002-051)
- GRADUATION PROGRAM 1948/04/15, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-052)
- COMMENCEMENT PROGRAM 1951/09/07, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-053)
- COMMENCEMENT PROGRAM 1952/09/12, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-054)
- COMMENCEMENT PROGRAM 1953/09/04, PROGRAM (Box-folder 002-055)
- COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS AND INVITATIONS 1954-1959, PROGRAMS (6), PRINTED CARDS (2)" (Box-folder 002-056)
- COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS AND INVITATIONS 1960-1969, PROGRAMS (9), PRINTED CARDS (6)" (Box-folder 002-057)
- COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS AND INVITATIONS 1970-1987, PROGRAMS (17), PRINTED CARDS (9)" (Box-folder 002-058)
- "INVITATION, PROGRAM, BROCHURE FROM CLOSING CEREMONIES" 1987/06/05-07, PROGRAM WITH ENVELOPE, PRINTED CARDS (2)" (Box-folder 002-059)
- ARTICLES ABOUT AHSN CLOSING 1986/ca., NEWSLETTERS/NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (7) (Box-folder 002-060)
- SENIOR BREAKFAST PROGRAMS 1972-1986, PROGRAMS (13) (Box-folder 002-061)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING STUDENT HANDBOOKS 1967-1973/ca., PAMPHLETS (5) (Box-folder 002-062)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING STUDENT HANDBOOKS 1974-1983, PAMPHLETS (5) (Box-folder 002-063)
- "CONFERENCE ON NURSING HISTORY PROGRAM, MISCELLANEOUS CARD" 1987/ca., PROGRAM, ACS WITH ENVELOPE" (Box-folder 003-001)
- "ARTICLES RE CAPPING, WHY A CAP?" 1973-1985, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (8), PAMPHLET" (Box-folder 003-002)
  THE ALEXANDRIA GAZETTE
- ARTICLES RE GRADUATION 1959-1981, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (16) (Box-folder 003-003)
  ALEXANDRIA AND MOUNT VERNON-LEE GLOBE; NORTHERN VIRGINIA SUN; THE ALEXANDRIA GAZETTE
- ARTICLES RE STUDENTS 1959-1981, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (26) (Box-folder 003-004)
  THE ALEXANDRIA GAZETTE; ANTIQUES OBSERVER; THE TIMES HERALD; THE ROSSLYN REVIEW; MALE NURSES
- ARTICLE RE AHNS'S FIRST PUBLIC GRADUATION 1915/05/08, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 003-005)
- ARTICLES RE AHSN 1970-1971, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (3) (Box-folder 003-006)
- ARTICLES RE AHSN HISTORY 1965-1975, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (4), TMs (2)" (Box-folder 003-007)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL PROGRESS NOTES CONTAINING ARTICLES RE SCHOOL OF NURSING 1956-1960, NEWSLETTERS (26), NEWSLETTERS (P) (3)" (Box-folder 003-008)
  ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL PROGRESS NOTES
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL PROGRESS NOTES CONTAINING ARTICLES RE SCHOOL OF NURSING 1961-1964, NEWSLETTERS (6), NEWSLETTERS (P) (2)" (Box-folder 003-009)
- HOSPITAL NEWSLETTERS CONTAINING ARTICLES RE SCHOOL OF NURSING 1964-1967, NEWSLETTERS (10) (Box-folder 003-010)
  ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL STETH-O-SCOOP
- HOSPITAL NEWSLETTERS CONTAINING ARTICLES RE SCHOOL OF NURSING 1967-1976, NEWSLETTERS (5), NEWSLETTERS (P) (3)" (Box-folder 003-011)
  ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL CAPSULE
- HOSPITAL NEWSLETTERS CONTAINING ARTICLES RE SCHOOL OF NURSING 1975-1983, NEWSLETTERS (7), NEWSLETTER (P)" (Box-folder 003-012)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL HIGHLIGHTS CONTAINING ARTICLES RE SCHOOL OF NURSING 1983-1984, NEWSLETTERS (11) (Box-folder 003-013)
  ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL HIGHLIGHTS
- MATERIALS RE: AFFILIATION WITH ST. ELIZABETH'S 1955/ca., TMs, PAMPHLET" (Box-folder 003-014)
- MATERIALS RE: AFFILIATION WITH ST. ELIZABETH'S 1954-1956, TMs (Box-folder 003-015)
  CONTAINS CORRESPONDENCE
- INFORMATION ON BLACK STUDENTS 1971/04/02, TMs (Box-folder 003-016)
- MATERIALS RE: ALUMNI 1971-1982, TMs (Box-folder 003-017)
- CONSTITUTION AND BY-LAWS OF THE ALUMNAE ASSOCIATION 1949-1971, PAMPHLETS (2) (Box-folder 003-018)
- MATERIALS RE: FACULTY ADVISORS N.D., TMs (2) (Box-folder 003-019)
- LETTER FROM HELEN A. STATTS TO NANCY STANDARD 1958/01/15, TL (CC) (Box-folder 003-020)
- ANNUAL COMBINED FACULTY MEETING MINUTES 1970-1976, TMs (10) (Box-folder 003-021)
- PROGRAMS OF ANNUAL COMBINED FACULTY MEETINGS 1966-1976, PROGRAMS (4) (Box-folder 003-022)
- PROGRAM OF ANNUAL MEETING OF COOPERATING AGENCIES 1983/04/22, PROGRAM (Box-folder 003-023)
- NURSING CAPS EXHIBIT N.D., PHOTOGRAPH (Box-folder 003-024)
- "MATERIALS RE: GROUND BREAKING, BUILDING, DEDICATION" 1959-1980, NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (6), PROGRAMS (2), PRINTED CARD" (Box-folder 003-025)
- NURSING CAPS N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (2) (Box-folder 003-026)
- PHOTOGRAPHS RE: CLASS OF 1964 1964/ca., NEWSLETTER PAGE (Box-folder 003-027)
- NURSING SCHOOL IS AMONG TOPS 1965/08/19, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 003-028)
  ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL GAZETTE
- PHOTOGRAPHS RE: NURSING EDUCATION WEEK N.D., NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (P) (2) (Box-folder 003-029)
- EXHIBIT TEXT N.D., TMs (Box-folder 003-030)
- GRADUATES OF THE ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING 1896-1955, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 003-031)
- PAMPHLETS RE: ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING 1951-1969/ca., PAMPHLETS (4) (Box-folder 003-032)
- LETTER FROM BERNICE M. NOAH TO ALUMNAE MEMBER 1962/ca., TLS (P) (Box-folder 003-033)
- NEWS RELEASE RE: MARTHA THORNTON ASHTON 1970/07/23, TMs (Box-folder 003-034)
- MATERIALS RE: FLORENCE NIGHTINGALE OATH N.D., TMs (2) (Box-folder 003-035)
- HOSPITAL SCHOOLS OF NURSING IN VIRGINIA N.D., PAMPHLET (Box-folder 003-036)
- SIX ARLINGTON NURSES RECEIVE CAPS 1965/04/27, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING (Box-folder 003-037)
  ARLINGTON SUBURBAN LEADER
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING 1974/ca., PHOTOGRAPH, PAMPHLET PAGES (2)" (Box-folder 003-038)
- LETTER FROM MYRTLE B. TAYLOR TO MARTHA MANNING 1987/02, ALS WITH ENVELOPE (Box-folder 003-039)
- "ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING GLEE CLUB, BASKETBALL TEAM" N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (3) (Box-folder 003-040)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING STUDENTS N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (2) (Box-folder 003-041)
- CAPPING CEREMONY N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (6) (Box-folder 003-042)
- MATERIALS RE: CARTER HALL 1969/ca., NEWSPAPER CLIPPING, PHOTOGRAPH, PAMPHLET PAGE" (Box-folder 003-043)
- "CLASS ROOM AND OFFICE BUILDING, 801 DUKE" N.D., PAMPHLET PAGE (Box-folder 003-044)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CLASSES N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (3) (Box-folder 003-045)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING STUDENT PINS N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (2) (Box-folder 003-046)
- TRADITIONAL BLACK BAND DINNER FOR NEW SENIORS (CLASS OF 1959) 1959/ca., PHOTOGRAPH (Box-folder 003-047)
- PINNING CEREMONY N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (2) (Box-folder 003-048)
- VARIOUS PLACES WITHIN HOSPITAL AND DIFFERENT HOSPITAL SITES N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (8) (Box-folder 003-049)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING STUDENTS 1900-1917, PHOTOGRAPHS (15) (Box-folder 003-050)
- MATERIALS RE: PRE-NURSING APTITUDE TEST 1958-1959, TMs (Box-folder 003-051)
- MATERIALS RE: NURSING NEEDS IN VIRGINIA 1960, TMs (Box-folder 003-052)
- MATERIALS RE: VIRGINIA HOSPITAL ASSOCIATION SURVEY OF NURSING EDUCATION PROGRAMS 1980, TMs (Box-folder 003-053)
- "HIGHLIGHTS OF NURSING IN VIRGINIA 1900-1975, CAPTAIN SALLY L. TOMPKINS C.S.A." 1966-1975, PAMPHLET, NEWSPAPER CLIPPING" (Box-folder 003-054)
- "MATERIALS RE: VIRGINIA LEAGUE FOR NURSING, VNA" 1967-1986, TMs (17), NEWSLETTERS (4), PAMPHLET" (Box-folder 004-001)
- VIRGINIA LEAGUE FOR NURSING BYLAWS 1981/04, PAMPHLET (Box-folder 004-002)
- MATERIALS RE: VIRGINIA STATE BOARD OF NURSE EXAMINERS 1950-1966, TMs (5), NEWSLETTERS (2), PAMPHLET PAGE" (Box-folder 004-003)
- MATERIALS RE: TRI-STATE REGIONAL PLANNING COUNCIL ON NURSING EDUCATION 1968-1971, TMs (Box-folder 004-004)
- SURVEY OF ADMISSION REQUIREMENTS OF DIPLOMA SCHOOLS OF NURSING IN VIRGINIA 1978/05/01, TMs (Box-folder 004-005)
- NATIONAL COMMISSION ON NURSING SURVEY OF SCHOOLS OF NURSING 1982 1982, TMs (Box-folder 004-006)
- SUMMARY REPORT OF THE INACTIVE REGISTERED NURSE STUDY 1980 1980, TMs (Box-folder 004-007)
- SURVEY ON COUNSELING NEEDS OF DIPLOMA SCHOOLS OF NURSING IN THE MIDDLE ATLANTIC AREA N.D., TMs (Box-folder 004-008)
- STUDENT NURSES' VIEW OF THE NURSING PROFESSION N.D., TMs (Box-folder 004-009)
- ILLINOIS MASONIC MEDICAL CENTER EVALUATION COMMITTEE N.D., TMs (Box-folder 004-010)
- RECRUITMENT SURVEY 1979/04/ca., TMs (Box-folder 004-011)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CLASS PHOTOGRAPHS 1908-1985, PHOTOGRAPHS (35), PAGE PROOF" (Box-folder 004-012)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING CLASS PHOTOGRAPHS 1908-1985, PHOTOGRAPHS (59), PHOTOGRAPHS (P) (4)" (Box-folder 004-013)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (13) (Box-folder 004-014)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING BLACK BAND DINNER N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (4), NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS (P) (2)" (Box-folder 004-015)
- ALEXANDRIA HOSPITAL SCHOOL OF NURSING STUDENTS N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (32) (Box-folder 004-016)
- CAPPING CEREMONIES N.D., PHOTOGRAPHS (13), PAGE PROOFS (P) (3)" (Box-folder 004-017)